If you leak the age of a person, you
also leak their birthday, their full
date of birth, right? Because what you
can do is you can just look at that age
and then find the day that it changes
and then you've got the person's
birthday.
Best part about hacking when you can
just, you know, critical thing, right?
>> [music]
>> All right, y'all. We've talked about
ThreatLocker ring-fencing a lot. We know
how it allows you to set ACLs and
policies for exactly what an application
is allowed to do in your network. But
today I'm going to tell you how it does
that, okay? Three technologies:
mini-filter drivers, Windows Filtering
Platform, and EX version kernel
notification routines. Mini-filter
drivers are essentially a hook or
callback for
IO requests, okay? So when you're trying
to write or read from a file, you can
create a hook with those and approve or
deny based off of the ThreatLocker ACL.
Windows Filtering Platform, similar
situation, but for connect bind
requests, right? You can say, "Okay,
hey, is this process allowed to talk to
port 443 over there on the internet? Yes
or no?" Approve or deny. Lastly, you've
got EX version kernel notification
routines. The EX version is important
because it allows you to approve or deny
versus just getting a notification from
the kernel.
Um and this is specific for um hooking
various native API calls like NT create
user process, which is what you'd use to
like spin up powershell.exe or something
like that, okay? So those three are very
useful to ThreatLocker's ring-fencing
core technology. Hope you enjoyed
learning how this is implemented. Check
out ThreatLocker if you think you would
benefit from something like that. All
right, let's go back to the show.
All right, Sub Hackers. Before we jump
into the episode this week, I got a
couple quick announcements in the this
week in bug bounty section. The first
one is actually the first three are from
YesWeHack. Uh
YesWeHack has dropped another complete
guide
and it's this time it's on OS command
injection. As I was reading through
this, there's a bunch of really good
summaries on what kind of techniques to
use here. You can see a bunch of
payloads where the
you know, command will break out of
various different contexts. One of the
things I've learned about command
injection is you will only find it if
you're looking for it, right?
And I I know a couple hackers, Franz and
Matias, that often find these bugs and
the reason they often find them is they
are often spraying payloads just like
these,
polyglots that include multiple contexts
or these specific ones that are right
here.
So grab some of these, integrate this
into your testing workflow and some of
these command injections will fall out.
I've I've seen it happen and it's amazed
me.
All right, y'all. Next up is another
piece from YesWeHack. This time we're
covering a critical auth bypass in
WordPress Azure AD SSO plugin. Man, I I
I'm not going to lie, guys. I had to say
that like I had to do like three
different takes because I can't say
that. Um but yeah, guys, this one's
pretty gnarly. Essentially, this allowed
unauthenticated attackers to log in as
arbitrary WordPress users if they're
using this plugin. So
this is essentially like an RCE, right?
Because if you can log in as any
WordPress user, log in as an admin,
upload some PHP code and then you've got
you can shell the server. So really bad.
Probe for this WordPress plugin, any of
you recon boys out there. Um the details
are laid out pretty cleanly here by
YesWeHack in the write-up down in the
proof of concept section. Essentially,
you can just provide a JWT token,
an ID token specifically,
that just says you are anybody, right?
And you can just
look, you can just submit blah.base64
encoded ID token.blah, right? And it's
just not checking the anything besides
that middle piece of the JWT.
Um so that's really bad.
So definitely go ahead and poke at this
if you haven't already. Great write-up
by YesWeHack. We'll link it in the
description.
All right, our last piece from YesWeHack
today is actually highlighting our boy
i2gl0w, who is a part of the CTBB team
and writes our hacker notes. So
shout-out to him. Those have been great
lately.
And this is just a bio on him. So if you
want to get to know i2gl0w better, he's
an excellent hacker
and this is a good way for you to
understand how he thinks, how he chooses
targets, what his favorite hacking tools
are,
that sort of thing. So we'll link that
down in the description as well,
highlighting our boy i2gl0w. I got to
get him on the pod sometimes, too. He'd
be he'd be a great addition.
All right, the last and perhaps most
exciting news item that we have for
today is Adobe is partnering with
EchoParty Miami
May 21st and May 22nd at the EchoParty
event to do a live hacking event.
To join the live hacking event, you can
submit all findings through the normal
Adobe bug bounty program. In scope is
Adobe Stock, Lightroom web,
Adobe Workfront, and they're increasing
bounties from tier one to tier three
for the AI bonus tier here for this live
hacking event. So if you're going to be
at EchoParty and want to participate in
this, definitely find the Adobe team and
we'll link more information in the
description below.
All right, I think that's it. Let's jump
to the main show.
All right, Sub Hackers. I am finally
back at home after
a marathon run of live hacking events.
So shout-out to HackerOne and Google for
their various live hacking events
they've been running.
I've been working long hours and I've
been traveling. So I'm not going to lie,
I'm pretty wiped.
Last episode Joseph and I were in Korea.
We kind of very sleepily at at like
midnight gave you guys some of the
takeaways from that event.
I proceeded to spend a couple days in
Korea
traveling around, spending some time
with my wife, and then came back to the
US and have been hit with an absolute
one-two punch of seasonal allergies here
in Virginia, just a [__] ton of pollen
and jet lag, which has been quite the
combo. And solo parenting while my wife
went over to Japan for a couple days to
see some friends. So
yeah, been a busy busy week. That being
said, this episode is going to be pretty
tight as well. My apologies for that,
but I do have some really interesting
content. So
yeah, I hope you guys get as much out of
it as I did when I was finding these
things.
It's definitely some good some good
takeaways. So let's go ahead and take a
look at those. We're going to do a
couple bugs and then we're going to do a
couple like just takeaways. So first up
is a protobuf-based XSS. So I wanted to
tell you guys about this because I've
been hacking on a target that uses
protobuf a lot
and I recently found an XSS that
requires you to actually send raw
protobuf. So binary level protobuf, not
like proto JSON or like base64 encoded
proto protobuf
over over the wire in an HTTP request
for it to work, okay? And this presents
a couple challenges and I'll try to
enumerate those here.
Anyway, so like if you could send the
request, then it would result in XSS. It
needs to be like a top-level navigation
in the browser, right? It's not checking
the content types, we can send it with
text plain. I thought it was not going
to be as hard as it was, but it was
pretty tricky. So let me tell you a
couple reasons why. One,
there's this thing called
a DOM string mutation that seems to
happen whenever
you actually add these this raw binary
to the DOM. So sometimes some of the
payloads will get a bit mangled. So you
really have to make sure your payload is
largely within the pure ASCII range,
which is
0x01 to 0x7f.
Otherwise, you're going to it's going to
cause some problems with it and get
mangled. So I kind of tweaked the
payload a lot to fit that range by
you know, inflating or deflating
you know, the size of various payloads,
trying to shift types as much as I could
or omit fields that were going to cause
problems if they weren't actually
strictly required in the in the protobuf
payload.
There was some flexibility there, which
was cool.
So after a lot of smithing, I got it
into that pure ASCII range.
The another problem is that if you have
an LF
line feed
character, which is 0x0a,
um
then and it is not immediately
you know, preceded by a
a 0x0d, a CR, a carriage return field,
then the browser is going to try to fix
that for you and put put in one,
which is very annoying and will break
your whole payload.
So the way that I kind of got around
this, oh and the protobuf, I'm looking
at my notes down here, that's why I keep
glancing down. But the protobuf field
for
um
you know, field number one and wire type
two, which is a a string, is going to be
0a. So you're not going to get away from
using getting an 0a in your actual
protobuf payload. So the way that I
actually got around this was
by buffering it up with a junk field
before that ended in 0d. Uh and so now
I've got what appears to be a um
a an a real CRLF, right? An 0d0a
in the hex, and then the browser doesn't
feel like it needs to fix that invalid
new line sequence there
and it was not mingling my my protobuf
payload. So that was awesome.
Obviously, this is really tricky because
protobuf is a length-based thing, right?
So if your if your lengths are off or if
there's a stray byte in there somewhere
and the the browser does anything funky,
then
uh your payload is going to completely
break. So, um that was one of the issues
that I ran into and got got through. The
other one was uh you kind of need to
send a or at least the way that I was
doing it, I think there are other ways
to do it, but you need to send a um
uh
equals character in your your payload
body. Um if you're even if you're doing
a text plain submission uh form
submission to get the top-level
navigation.
Um so, you need somewhere there's going
to be a equals sign, right? And
something's going to be the the the key
on one side and the value on the other
side and the equal in the middle, right?
So, uh how I ended up solving this one
was I padded out a field um you know, I
that had the um the 0x3d
character as the length, right? Where I
needed it to be. Um so, that it wouldn't
heck up the
the string before or the string after um
with some of these weird rules for keys
versus values um in a form submission.
So, just had to align that properly to
get it to not break um and get most of
the values in the um
or most of the data in the value, which
is a little bit less liberally um
tweaked by the uh
by the browser. Um so, we we have a lot
more flexibility there.
Um
So, that was another challenge was
getting that um equal sign in there. And
then the last challenge was really
interesting, which is the browser will
actually append a um
uh CRLF sequence at the end of your
submission whenever you send a form.
Which was really annoying to me. I'm
like, okay, well, that might just do me
in because I need my whole, you know,
protobuf payload needs to end with CRLF.
Um but actually, the way I solved this
in the end was define a string field at
the end with a length that is two
bytes longer than the length I actually
provided it. So, when
So, when the browser actually appends
the two uh characters at the end, that
will get slurped up into the defined
string at the last, you know, field of
the protobuf and it will actually not
mess with the the byte offsets or um not
parse it as extraneous data or anything.
It'll just parse it as a part of the
string that we already defined. So,
let's say I the last, you know, um
character or the last string that I
defined was four uh bytes long, I would
only give it two bytes. So, when the
browser filled in those other two bytes,
it would be that full four-byte string.
Um
so, anyway, just uh interesting little
um solution there if you're ever dealing
with protobuf uh that you actually need
to send over the wire in um
an actual like top-level navigation via
a form um to trigger an XSS or
otherwise, then uh those are some tips
and tricks that I had along the way.
Um all right.
>> [laughter]
>> Let's let's keep moving. Um up next was
the This was one that uh is not actually
that crazy, but I like the mentality, so
I wanted to tell you guys about this.
So, um I found a way on a program
recently to leak the age of a person.
Excuse me.
of a person. Um and the age of the
person is an interesting thing to leak.
Sure, it has some impact on itself. But
as I was sitting there thinking about
it, if you leak the age of a person, you
also leak their birthday, their full
date of birth, right? Because what you
can do is you can just look at that age
and then find the day that it changes
and then you've got the person's
birthday.
>> [laughter]
>> Right? Um and then the full date of
birth, which is a lot more helpful in my
opinion.
Um obviously, you could do some brute
forcing and stuff like that. But if
we're talking about like PII disclosure,
getting the actual month and day as well
as the year is valuable. Uh so, I just
wanted to
you know, throw that out there for y'all
as thinking about
whenever you're leaking some data, try
to think about how that data can change
over time and if that can give you any
additional information. Uh and you might
be able to find some additional impact
for your bugs.
Um okay.
Uh just a couple more takeaways and then
I got to wrap this episode. Um CSPTs
work not only on web apps, but also on
desktop apps or any other type of app. I
was hacking on a desktop app
specifically recently and I was able to
essentially incur uh
HTTP request with user-supplied input in
the path remotely from a different
machine, okay? And uh this one
specifically came in through sockets,
web sockets, but um it actually was able
to
you know, I was able to supply a path
traversal and truncate the path and hit
a completely different endpoint. Um and
that ended up having some really good
impact. And I was just kind of sitting
there thinking about this and I I guess
I just sort of um assumed beforehand
that this was more of a web-based
vulnerability, but pretty much anything
that interacts with HTTP can be CSPT.
Um because uh traversals are such a key
part of pathing in
um in most HTTP environments. So, just
think about that as well. I I I know
that sometimes as web hackers, we
struggle to make the pivot to other
types of hacking, whether it be IoT or
desktop apps or binaries or whatever. Um
This is an an attack that can be used
fairly universally um because HTTP is
really is really common even outside of
um strictly web apps, okay? Just a
thought. Um
and and I'm also interested in kind of
thinking about other types of
vulnerabilities
that are more present outside of uh just
the web environment where we can sort of
take those over. So, if you have any of
those, uh maybe drop them in the pod
talk channel in the critical thinking
Discord um
Yeah, I think that there's definitely
going to be more. I'm going to I'm going
to keep uh spinning on that. Um okay.
Another one that is really interesting,
another takeaway that I had.
Guys, capital letters are really
overpowered,
>> [laughter]
>> okay?
Uh I was hacking with with somebody, I'm
not going to say who, recently and we
just found a ton of bypasses using
capital letters, okay?
I'll give you an example of one of them.
This is This one is just um one of like
three that we used to find
vulnerabilities uh in the past couple
months, okay?
First, uh we had a scenario where if a
specific cookie was not present that is
pretty much always pre- present uh when
a request was issued to a specific
endpoint, it would result in a
vulnerability, okay? So, how do we get
this cookie not not issued? Well, we
could, you know, put it in a
credentialed iframe or whatever, but we
kind of needed access to the victim's
session as well, right? So, we've got
this like catch-22 situation of okay,
how do I um send a request without just
this one cookie while keeping the other
cookies? Was essentially what we needed
to do.
And the way we ended up solving this was
by sending a request to the same path,
but with one character switched to a
capital letter, okay? And what that did
was uh technically, that is a different
path. The back end was processing it as
the same path, but the browser was not
sending the cookie to that path because
the cookie was hard scoped to a specific
path that did not have that capital
letter, right? So, the path um attribute
for the cookie was set to, let's call
it, abc lowercase. And when we
sent the request to abc
uppercase, that cookie would not be
sent, right? So, these uh cookies' path
definitions, they're they're
case-sensitive. And a lot of times, our
paths that we're dealing with on HTTP
servers are not case-sensitive. Um so,
just keep that in mind. Obviously,
there's uh encoding tricks and stuff
like that you could do. But in this
situation, it was actually simple as uh
lowercase and uppercase letters. Um
There was
As soon as some of these bugs get
resolved, I'm going to come back on the
pod and talk about them uh
cuz there were some other weird ones
that we solved with uppercase uh
letters.
So, just be on the look out up for that.
I feel like it's kind of like a uh
you know, simple method, but it's it's
very prevalent. Okay. Um
Two last takeaways.
Both sort of relate to um
clickjacking or getting uh a new tab
open inside of your browser with
top-level navigation, okay? So, we're
dealing with some client-side stuff
here.
So, um
I ran into a situation recently where I
needed to be able to CSRF somebody to
set a cookie
and I needed to do this inside of a
iframe
because of the constraints of the
attack. And then inside of that iframe,
there would be rendered a link. And if
the user clicked that link and did a
top-level navigation with it, it would
result in a CSRF.
Um so, essentially, what I ended up
doing here was uh performing a
clickjacking attack and the person would
need to control-click one button on the
screen and then their account would get
taken over, right? Um cuz I could
trigger the the login CSRF and then they
click the button and then bad stuff
happens, okay? Um so,
I hadn't really used that control-click
to open up a top-level navigation from
within an iframe trick before. Uh so, I
thought that was a pretty interesting
one that you guys might want to know
about. Um once again, clickjacking, very
impactful vulnerability type in my
opinion uh if you do it correctly, okay?
Note that last caveat, if you do it
correctly. Um very important. So, keep
that technique in mind. And then last
but not least, I was just doing a little
like
brainstorming before this episode and I
was thinking like,
"Okay,
if I need to do a window.open,
I need to get a user gesture, right?
That's the technical term that you use
to get a window open uh without a pop-up
block in uh in modern browsers." And I
was looking into what that is, and I've
just always kind of thought of that as a
click,
but it's not only a click. You can also
get this from uh a key down event, which
I think is a lot easier to get in some
scenarios. I mean, really this isn't a
problem very much because you can always
just perceive um get the user to
perceive it as like one of those accept
cookies uh pop-ups, and then you get a
free click whenever, right? Really
useful for POCs.
Um but just keep that in mind as well
that you can also do a window open
without a pop-up block from a key down
event.
Um the last thing that I wanted to
mention was whenever you do need this
control click,
uh I realized that you can actually like
make buttons unclickable until you are
holding the control key. So, that makes
it a lot easier to like cerebrally
convince the victim that they need to
control click something is uh you can
actually hide UI elements if the user's
not currently holding down the control
key. Um so, just think that about that
as well. It's much easier to program
these things with AI nowadays, so um
it makes your POC a lot cleaner. Also,
definitely want to cover it on the pod.
Just popped into my brain. Uh I don't
don't have time to do it today, but the
research by Lyra on uh SVG enhanced uh
clickjacking is unfreakingbelievable.
You can make literally, you know,
responsive buttons via uh SVG magic
essentially um
overlaid, you know, for clickjacking
purposes, right? So, with the problem
with clickjacking is, right, there's an
invisible iframe in front of it. So,
when you click it, it it you know, it
doesn't actually do anything. You don't
see the UI, you know, button depress or
anything like that. Um but with these
SVG
magic things that that Lyra does, uh you
can actually make it happen. So, anyway,
I really want to build a library out of
that. Um I think that that is a really
useful and mass applicable technique. Um
so, anyway, I'll link that research in
the description.
Um all right, guys. That's all I got for
this week. I'm sorry. We're going to
bring the heat coming coming forward the
next couple weeks. We've got a lot of
great interviews lined up, and we've
also got our first meta-analysis
episode, which I'm excited to present to
you guys. All right, that's a wrap for
this week. Peace.
And that's a wrap on this episode of
Critical Thinking. Thanks so much for
watching till the end, y'all. If you
want more Critical Thinking content
[music] uh or if you want to support the
show, head over to ctbb.show/discord.
You can hop in the community. There's
lots of great high-level [music] hacking
discussion happening there on top of the
masterclasses, hackalongs, exclusive
content, and a full-time Hunter's Guild
if you're a full-time hunter. It's a
great time, trust me.
>> [music]
>> All right, I'll see you there.